They have a plan!
Battlestar Galactica: The Plan is a science fiction, action,
drama film directed by Edward James Olmos.
When the initial Cylon attack against the Twelve Colonies fails to achieve complete extermination of human life as planned,
twin Number Ones (Cavils) embedded on Galactica and Caprica must improvise to destroy the human survivors.
Commander William Adama, played by Edward James Olmos.
Brother Cavil, played by Dean Stockwell.
Samuel Anders, played by Michael Trucco.
Lt. Sharon 'Boomer' Valerii, played by Grace Park.
Colonel Saul Tigh, played by Michael Hogan.
Leoben Conoy, played by Callum Keith Rennie.
Battlestar Galactica: The Plan is a television film set in the reimagined
version of the fictional Battlestar Galactica universe.
It consists of newly filmed material as well as a compilation of
footage from the 2003 miniseries and 2004 TV series.
The miniseries and first two seasons of Battlestar Galactica are retold with more
emphasis on the Cylon perspective and their plan to wipe out the human race.
The story follows two versions of the Cylon known as Cavil, one of whom admits they
may have made a mistake, with the story being told in flashback.
The "Final Five" Cylons are featured prominently.
The film premiered exclusively on DVD, Blu-ray Disc and
digital download on October 27, 2009.
It premiered on January 10, 2010 on Syfy, on April 2, 2010 on Sky Premiere in
the United Kingdom, and on August 6, 2011 on Space in Canada.
The film explores themes of fighter pilot, body double, human
heart, battlestar galactica, based on tv series.
The tone is emotional and thought_provoking.